Guide to the Lesly Lempert Collection, 1987-1994.
Lempert, Lesly Collection
- Series I. Periodicals
  - (Article): Low grants are driving olim to prostitution, January 17, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): Home on the range, April 26, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): US-Israeli Bond Remains Firm, June 20, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
    Producer: George D. Moffett III, Christian Science Monitor
  - (Article): US Aid Cornucopia Flows to Israel, June 21, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): Resettlement Costs Put Strain On Israeli Credit, June 25, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): Israel's Role As US Ally Debated, June 27, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): Sharon tells Ma'aleh Adumim at 15th anniversary: Jerusalem area to have a million Jews, July 3, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): Government giving land for free to Jewish developers in territories, July 28, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): In a political trap of our own making, August 9, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
    Producer: Ariel Sharon, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): Ecology group protests 'land grab' by ministry for haredim, September 21, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): Sharon okays housing for haredi groups, September 21, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): U.S.-Israeli Quarrel: Missed Messages, September 25, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): New Israeli Town Abuts West Bank's Border, September 25, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): Settlement or neighborhood? Left and right disagree, October 6, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): 1% of olim settle in territories, October 11, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): True Believers: American Jews Are Settling in Israel's Embattled Occupied Territories-and Further Complicating the Search for Peace, October 13, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
    Producer: Daniel Williams, Los Angeles Times Magazine
  - (Article): A House Divided, November 1, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
    Producer: Carl Schrag, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): The Myth of Irreversibility, November 25, 1991; photocopy (Box 8, Folder 413)
    Producer: Mark Taylor, Marty Rosenbluth, The Nation
  - (Article): MKs allege that colonel informed settlers of IDF operational plan, December 8, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
    Producer: Asher Wallfish, Alon Pinkas
  - (Article): E. Jerusalem settler groups confer to coordinate effort, speed settlement, December 19, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): Sharon built 18,000 homes in Judea and Samaria, say 2 MKs, January 8, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): Sharon: Settlements are excuse for housing loan guarantee delays, January 12, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): Israelis Stepping Up Settlement Construction, January 23, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): The Peace Now show, January 23, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): The Second Conquest of the City of David, January 30, 1992; photocopy (Box 8, Folder 413)
    Producer: Isabel Kershner, Jerusalem Report
  - (Article): The Unsettling Israel Accord: Rabin makes peace with the United States, but not with the Palestinians, August 13, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 413)
    Producer: Edmund R. Hanauer, San Diego Union-Tribune
  - (Article): An Arab village ponders the loss of its lands, May 10 [?] (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): And all for the sake of Greater Israel, August 19 [?] (Box 8, Folder 413)
    Producer: Susan Hattis Rolef
  - (Article): Defense Ministry stops placement of more caravan homes in Revava, [?] (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): Demonstrations rock tense Silwan, [?] (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - (Article): Some News Items Most US Newspapers Overlooked, [?] (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - [Articles pertaining to Torture], October 22, 1989--April 16, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 414)
  - (Article): 'You Are a Dog', October 22, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 414)
  - (Article): Amnesty International reports on administrative detention of Palestinians, January 8, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 414)
  - (Article): Watching Rights, June 24, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 414)
    Producer: Aryeh Neier, The Nation
  - (Article): Inside an Israeli Prison, July 18, 1991; photocopy (Box 8, Folder 414)
    Producer: Ari Shavit, New York Review of Books
  - (Article): The Shabac and Torture in Detention Centers, December 2, 1991; photocopy (Box 8, Folder 414)
    Producer: Ariela Ringel-Hofmann, Al-Fajr
  - (Article): Beinish: 'Moderate' Pressure is a Last Resort, April 15, 1992; photocopy (Box 8, Folder 414)
  - (Article): Court Postpones Decision on 'Torture Petition', April 16, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 414)
  - [Articles pertaining to the Water Shortage], January 21, 1990--October 19, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Water, water everywhere, January 21, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Leon Moss
  - (Article): Middle East's Cup Runneth Dry, March 8, 1990; photocopy (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Jordan faces drought, March 12, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Water to be rationed for agriculture, March 12, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Larry Derfner, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): If Jordan Valley Wells Run Dry…, March 14, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): The water bureaucracy, April 11, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): The risks of reopening universities, May 16, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Joshua Brilliant
  - (Article): Future Water Shortages Threaten Middle East Peace, May 25, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Water most important factor in Arab-Israeli conflict, says experts, October 15, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Sami Abu Ghazaleh, Al-Fajr
  - (Article): Water Scarcity, December 6, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Joan Gray, Henry Gray, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): Shortage of water could mean phasing out of some farm branches, December 30, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Israel Puts the Squeeze on: Politics and Pumping Drive, January/March 1990; photocopy (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Gershon Baskin, Challenge
  - (Article): The water crisis: 25 years of bad management, January 3, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Water we going to do about it?, January 4, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): What to do about water, January 4, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Kinneret red-line level may change in summer, January 8, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Water supply cut to all consumers, February 2, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Water crisis drain the national carrier, March 18, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Water, water everywhere, March 24, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Zeynep Alemdar
  - (Article): Eleventh-hour thinking on water, March 25, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Susan Hattis Rolef, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): Israel and China hold workshop on water, April 26, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Ted Plafker, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): We need a regional 'Marshall Plan' for water, May 17, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Edmund de Rothschild
  - (Article): Wells of conflict on the West Bank, June 1, 1991; photocopy (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Fred Pearce, New Scientist
  - (Article): Not stealing the river, June 7, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Abraham Rabinovich
  - (Article): Public saving water, officials dragging feet, June 15, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Pupil increase means portable classrooms, August 6, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Surie Ackerman, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): Water crisis drips down to the public, August 9, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Ishai resists PM's advice to take extended leave, August 13, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): New job park threatens water, August 16, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): The water issue lies at the heart of politics, August 16, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Allan E. Shapiro, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): New water chief aims at efficiency, August 19, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Mekorot gets NIS 105m to expand water supply, August 22, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Peace talks at water level, September 2, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Public's water saving measures keeping Kinneret level high, September 5, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Subsidizing drought, September 8, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Peres discusses water in Turkey, Septemebr 11, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Michal Yudelman
  - (Article): U.S. asked to press Syria on water parley, September 26, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Allison Kaplan, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): Water Often Is a Divisive Issue In the Fractious Middle East, October 30, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Peter Waldman, Wall Street Journal
  - (Article): More water no big deal for the Dead Sea, February 14, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Jacob Wirtschafter
  - (Article): Peace through a water plan, February 17, 1992; photocopy (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Boaz Wachtel, Al-Fajr
  - (Article): Mekorot begins work on Eilat desalination plan, July 2, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Water being pumped into Kinneret on purpose-water commissioner, July 9, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Zaslavsky: Technology could solve Middle East's water problems, September 20, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Howard Lerner, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): Mekorot well project helps water supply, September 22, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Water Committee discussed technical subjects, reports head of the Palestinian team, September 28, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Abdel Salam Musa, Al-Fajr
  - (Article): Struggle for Water Looms as Most Difficult Hurdle in Mideast, October 10, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - (Article): Kinneret's lows are high times for history, April 26, [?] (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Abraham Rabinovich, Jerusalem Post
  - (Article): Water: The Ultimate Frontier, [?] (Box 8, Folder 415)
    Producer: Boaz Wachtel
  - [Articles pertaining to Zvi Kesse], October 18, 1983--November 25, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 416)
  - (Article): Q&A: Israeli Educator Makes His Case for a Palestinian State, October 18, 1983; photocopy (Box 8, Folder 416)
    Producer: Ed Fishbein, International Herald Tribune
  - (Article): Gloomy Sociologist, November 25, 1983; photocopy (Box 8, Folder 416)
    Producer: Jerome Green
  - (Article): Israel On Path to Irrelevance?, [?]; photocopy (Box 8, Folder 416)
    Producer: Manuel Chait
  - [Articles pertaining to Proposition W], August 21, 1988--August 26, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 417)
  - (Article): Palestine Powderkeg on Ballot, August 21, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 417)
    Producer: Bruce Petit, San Francisco Progress
  - (Article): Fireworks Likely Over Pro-Palestinian Prop W in S.F., August 26, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 417)
    Producer: Tamar Kaufman, Northern California Jewish Bulletin
  - (Article): Muddle East, [?] (Box 8, Folder 418)
    Producer: Art Silverman
  - [Miscellaneous articles on Israeli and Palestinian Affairs], 1988--1992 (Box 8, Folder 419)
  - *Hebrew translation in Red folder? (Box 8, Folder 420)
  - He is Independent, So He Does Not Need Instructions, June 28, 1991; typescript, 7 leaves (Box 8, Folder 421)
    Producer: Alon Pinkas, Davar
  - Twilight Zone: Occupation Authorities Claim that Police Disregard Official Policy, March 23, 1992; transmission, 6 leaves (Box 8, Folder 422)
    Producer: Amira Hass, Ha'aretz
  - Ansar 2: Detention, Humiliation and Intimidation, June, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 423)
    Producer: Anita Vitullo, Palestine Human Rights Information Center (PHRIC), HRREF/DataBase Project
  - Israel's War By Bureaucracy, [1988?] (Box 8, Folder 424)
    Producer: Anita Vitullo, Palestine Human Rights Information Center (PHRIC), Human Rights Research and Education Foundation (HRREF)
  - Palestinian Women Post-Intifada: Several Steps Back, [?]; draft, typescript, 4 leaves (Box 8, Folder 425)
    Producer: Anita Vitullo
  - Double Jeopardy: PLO Strategy Toward Israel and Jordan, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 426)
    Producer: Asher Susser, The Washington Institute for Near East Policy
  - A Special Report: Coalition Litigation for Equality of Education, [1991?]; publication and draft (Box 8, Folder 427)
    Producer: Avigdor Feldman, Hussein abu Hussein, American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition
  - [Reivew of the facts and legal proceedsings regarding the appeal of five people convicted of the murder of Danny Katz], 15-Nov-88 (Box 8, Folder 427 A)
    Producer: Avigdor Feldman
  - Hofesh ha-hitarganot be-Yisrael, [?] (Box 8, Folder 428)
    Producer: Avishai Erlikh, Qol Qore, American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition
  - Palestinian Women and Israeli Human Rights Violations, [?]; draft, typescript, 7 pages (Box 8, Folder 429)
    Producer: Beth Goldring
  - Women's Human Rights Project: Background Paper: Problems in Palestinian Residence Following the Gulf War, October 10, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 430)
    Producer: Beth Goldring, Women's Research and Training Society
  - Women's Human Rights Project: Problems in Statistical Assessment of Family Reunifications., September 4, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 430)
  - No More Exit Permits, July 24, 1991; typescript, 1 page (Box 8, Folder 431)
    Producer: Dan Izenberg, Asher Wallfish
  - Growing a Constitution: Reconciling Liberty and Community in Israel and the United States, Winter 1994 (Box 8, Folder 432)
    Producer: Donna E. Arzt, Law & Social Inquiry: Journal of the American Bar Foundation (Reprint: v. 19, no. 1, Winter 1994: p. 253-274)
  - Ule-faate mizrah-qadimah, October 18, 1991; article, photocopy, 1 page (Box 8, Folder 433)
    Producer: Elisha Efrat, [Newspaper unidentified]
  - When the Whole is Greater than the Sum of all Parts, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 434)
    Producer: Elmer Berger, The Palestine Yearbook of International Law (Reprint: v. 5, 1989: p. 406-454)
  - An Open Message to Our Israeli Friends, [?]; typescript, 4 leaves (Box 8, Folder 435)
    Producer: George Abu-Karim (pseudonym), Beit Sahour-Jerusalem dialogue of Palestinians and Jewish Israelis
  - Moroccan Desert: Hardscrabble Life: An Exotic, Unyielding Land, All But Forgotten, March 12, 1990; photocopy, 3 leaves (Box 8, Folder 436)
    Producer: George D. Moffett III, Christian Science Moniter
  - The Water Crisis: The Next Middle East Conflict?, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 437)
    Producer: Dr. George Gruen, Simon Wiesenthal Center
  - Gulf Crisis: Baghdad, Jerusalem and Beirut, October 2, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 438)
    Producer: Ghassan Rubeiz, CICARWS, WCC
  - Baynish: The Landau Commission did not Give the G.S.S. a Carte Blanche to Apply Pressure during Interrogations, April 15, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 439)
    Producer: Gideon Alon, Ha'aretz, Public Committee Against Torture in Israel
  - The Landau Report did not Eradicate the Use of Torture, September 16, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 440)
  - Ma'arekhet ha-misui ba-Gadah ha-ma'aravit uva-retsu'at 'Azah (Box 8, Folder 441)
    Producer: Hadarah Lazar, B'Tselem
    Volume/Number: 1990
  - ha-Gidushim ha-sheqatim, September 8, 1989; photocopy, 1 page (Box 8, Folder 442)
    Producer: Halad Abu-Io'amah, Yerushalayim
  - Transcript of conversation with Sharon Shehav, [?]; 3 leaves (Box 8, Folder 443)
    Producer: Hanatia Blumfield, American Jewish Congress Director of Women's Committee
  - The Two "Jerusalems", July 21, 1990; photocopy, 1 page (Box 8, Folder 444)
    Producer: Hillel Bardin
  - Minority Report of the National Lawyers Guild on Treatment of Palestinians in Israeli Occupied Territories, [?]; photocopy, 11 leaves (Box 8, Folder 445)
    Producer: Howard Dickstein, National Lawyers Guild
  - Treatment of Palestinians in Israeli-Occupied West Bank and Gaza, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 445)
    Producer: National Lawyers Guild
  - [Translations from the Israeli press, 10-17 April 1992 ], [1992]; typescript: 5 leaves (Box 8, Folder 446)
    Producer: Israel Shahak (translator from Hebrew)
  - Palestinian Children: Empowered, Handicapped, Traumatized, [1992?] (Box 8, Folder 447)
    Producer: James A. Graff, Near East Cultural and Educational Foundation (NECEF)
  - This Land is Our Land: The West Bank Under Israeli Occupation, [1992?]; fax transmittal, p. 52-53, 58-61 (Box 8, Folder 448)
    Producer: Jan Metzger, Martin Orth, Christian Sterzing
  - Creeping Transfer' in the West Bank: Israel's Campaign of Family Deunification, January 31, 1990, February 2, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 449)
    Producer: Jerry Levin
  - Israel Turns "Creeping Transfer" into "Hidden Transfer": Its Campaign of Family Deunification Continues, February 5, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 450)
  - Al-Haq's Response to The Chapter on Israel and the Occupied Territories in the U.S. State Department's "Country Reports on Human Rights Practicse for 1984", December, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 451)
    Producer: Joost R. Hiltermann, Al-Haq, Law in the Service of Man
  - The Quiet Deportations: Tens of Arabs from Judea and Samaria are Being Transferred Every Month for Bureaucratic Reasons, September 8, 1989; photocopy, 1 page (Box 8, Folder 452)
    Producer: Khaled Abu To'ameh
  - A New Zionism, April, 1989; photocopy, p. 48-53 (Box 8, Folder 453)
    Producer: Leonard Fein, Moment
  - Conversation with Judith Green, May 7, 1989; transcription, 6 leaves (Box 8, Folder 454)
    Producer: Lesley I. Lempert
  - Notes from a conversation with Sharon Shenhav on October 18, 1993, October 18, 1993; typescript, 5 leaves (Box 8, Folder 455)
  - Confrontations: Israeli Life in the Year of the Uprising, 1988; photocopy, p. 1-239 (Box 8, Folder 456)
    Producer: Louis Rapoport, Quinlan Press
  - Population and Labour Force in Gaza Strip, October, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 457)
    Producer: Dr. Mahmoud K. Okasha, Arab Thought Forum
  - The Day After the Palestinian State: Arab and Jewish Attitudes in Israel, Winter 1991; photocopy, p. 23-26 (Box 8, Folder 458)
    Producer: Majid al-Haj, Middle East Focus
  - Salaam-Shalom International Student Coalition, [?]; typescript, 1 page (Box 8, Folder 459)
    Producer: Mark Federman
  - The Political Significance of Israeli Court Systems, [1991]; typescript, 57 leaves (Box 8, Folder 460)
    Producer: Martin Edelman, American Political Science Association (Annual Meeting, Washington, D.C., August 29-September 1, 1991)
  - The Utility of a Written Constitution: Free Exercise of Religion in Israel and the United States, [1991]; typescript, 20 leaves (Box 8, Folder 461)
    Producer: Martin Edelman, Association for Israel Studies (Annual Meeting, Barnard College, June 9 & 10, 1991)
  - Eyeless in Gaza, [1988?]; typescript, 5 leaves (Box 8, Folder 462)
    Producer: Martin Garbus, Arthur Eisenberg
    Volume/Number:
  - The Unofficial, Incomplete List of Peace-Protest-Coexistance & Justice Groups in Israel, July, 1990; typescript, 15 leaves (Box 8, Folder 463)
    Producer: Maxine Kaufman Nunn, P.O.
  - The West Bank Handbook: A Political Lexicon, April, 1990; photocopy, p. 1-219 (Box 8, Folder 464)
    Producer: Meron Benvenisti, Ziad Abu-Zayed, Danny Rubinstein
  - Michal Schwartz-Biographical Information, April, 1992; photocopy, 1 page (Box 8, Folder 465)
  - The "Green Line" Case: A Research Proposal Submitted to American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition, Inc., August, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 466)
    Producer: Mousa Karayanni, Ph.D.
  - Palestinian Health: Toward a Healthy Development Strategy in the West Bank and Gaza Strip, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 467)
    Producer: Mustafa Barghouti, M.D., Union of Palestinian Medical Relief Committees
  - Appeal: Palestinians in the Occupied Territories Continue to Face the War Unprotected, January 20, 1991; transmittal (Box 8, Folder 467 A)
  - The Revolution is Us, Too, April-June 1991; photocopy, p. 16-18 (Box 8, Folder 468)
    Producer: Nahla Abdo, Connexions 36
  - Israel and the Intifada: The High Price of Repression, [?]; typescript, 8 leaves (Box 8, Folder 469)
    Producer: Nancy Murray
  - Hayim, herut u-shvayon bi-mesoret ha-yehudit, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 470)
    Producer: No'am Zohar, Shomre Mishpat, Rabbanim le-ma'an zekhuyot ha-adam
  - The Use of International Human Rights Law in ACLU Cases, June 15-18, 1987; typescript, 12 pages (Box 8, Folder 471)
    Producer: Paul Hoffman, American Civil Liberities Union
  - [Sermon delivered by Rabbi Sanford Ragins on Yom Kippur Morning], September 27, 1982; typescript, 3 pages (Box 8, Folder 472)
    Producer: Rabbi Sanford Ragins
  - Planning and Housing Issues in East Jerusalem: A Report for the Society of St Yves In Response to High Court Petition #1901/94, June, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 473)
    Producer: Sarah Kaminker and Associates
  - Challenge/Etgar, May 1990, January/March 1991--November/December 1991, May 1990--December 1991 (Box 8, Folder 474)
    Producer: Shimon Tzabar (publisher)
    Volume/Number: [1.]2, 2.1--2.6
  - Challenge/Etgar, July/August 1991 (Box 8, Folder 474)
  - Challenge/Etgar, January/February 1992--November/December 1992, January--December 1992 (Box 8, Folder 475)
    Volume/Number: 3.1--3.6 (11--16)
  - Challenge/Etgar, January/February 1993--January/February 1996 (Box 8, Folder 476)
    Volume/Number: 4.1--4.4, 5.2--5.3, 5.5--5.6, 6.2--6.3, 7.1
  - [Transcript of speech delivered by Shulamit Aloni], [May 12, 1981?]; typescript, 16 pages (Box 8, Folder 477)
    Producer: Shulamit Aloni
  - Les détentions administratives pour raisons de sécurité (Tranduction française: Kupferman (from Hebrew?)), 1989?; 5 leaves (Box 8, Folder 478)
    Producer: Tamar Pelleg-Sryck
  - Report: Victims of the Intifada, May, 1988; typescript, 6 leaves (Box 8, Folder 479)
    Producer: Dr. Uri Elmaliah, (various authors)
  - Beit Sahour, [1989?]; unpublished typescript, 308 leaves (Box 8, Folder 480)
    Producer: Virginia Olsen Baron
  - Just One Straight Line, August 2, 1991; multiple versions (Box 8, Folder 481)
    Producer: Yael Ashkenazi (author), Kol Ha'ir, Peretz Kidron
  - British Motivations Behind the Balfour Declaration, November 4, 1992; college paper, 11 leaves (Box 8, Folder 482)
    Producer: Yael Lempert
  - When Judge and Hangman are One and the Same Person, June 14, 1991; typescript, 4 leaves (Box 8, Folder 483)
    Producer: Yehuda Litani, Al-HaMishmar
  - Final Reading Assignment for EXP 65 F: Israeli-Palestinian Conflict, November 23, 1993 (compilation date); photocopies of articles (Box 8, Folder 484)
    Producer: (various authors)
  - (article): Mine Enemy: Aharon, Amalia, Salah & Dina, July/August 1988 (Box 8, Folder 484)
    Producer: Aharon Barnea, Amalia Barnea
  - (article): Peace Process: Israeli and Palestinian Women, Fall 1991 (Box 8, Folder 484)
    Producer: Nabila Espanioli, Dalia Sachs
  - (3 excerpts): Voices From A Promised Land: Palestinian and Israeli Peace Activists Speak their Hearts, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 484)
    Producer: Curbstone Press, Penny Rosenwasser
  - (2 excerpts): Confession from a Jericho Jail: "What Happened When I Refused to Fight Palestinians", 1992 (Box 8, Folder 484)
    Producer: Stephen Langur
  - (article): The Letter to Bashir, May, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 484)
    Producer: René Backmann, New Outlook, Middle East Monthly
  - Fathers and their Babies: Palestinian Style, [?]; typescript (Box 9, Folder 528)
    Producer: Dr. Veronica Wolf Cohen
  - [Information regarding Hanan Ashrawi], September 6, 1986--[August 26, 1991] (Box 9, Folder 529)
    Producer: [various publications]
  - (CV): Hanan Mikhail-Ashrawi, September 6, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 529)
    Producer: Hanan Mikhail-Ashrawi
  - (Poem): Metamorphosis: Ramallah, June 10, 1989, September, 1989; typescript (Box 9, Folder 529)
  - (Poem): Women and Things, October, 1989; typescript (Box 9, Folder 529)
  - (Poem): Interrogation, [?]; typescript (Box 9, Folder 529)
  - Alert, February 6, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 530)
    Producer: Mercy Corps International
  - Statement by National Figures from Occupied Palestine, August 15, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 531)